Um, hi. The sun isn't the center of our
solar system. At least not right now.
Stick with me here. Everything with
gravity pulls on each other. So, the sun
pulls on us, but we pull a little bit on
the sun, too. And we're teeny, so we
barely make a difference. But Jupiter is
big. It's so massive that Jupiter
actually never orbits the sun at all.
They both orbit this shared point that
actually sits outside the sun. And now
if you add up all the planets with all
their different orbits and all their
masses, you get this one shared center
for the whole solar system. And it
moves. Sometimes it's inside the sun,
but sometimes it's outside. The last
time it was inside the sun was 2016, and
the center of our solar system won't be
back inside the sun until 2027. But what
if Earth actually was the center of our
solar system? You wouldn't like it. to
see what would happen.